{
    "id": "48fc95001ec84212bb28f79428e34393",
    "title": "Simple, compound or complex",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "6e7b878b83ee405b9e54771249a83abb",
            "title": "Simple, Compound Or Complex",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "We went out in spite of the rain.",
                    "description": "The given sentence has only one finite verb and hence one clause. So it is a simple sentence.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple",
                        "Complex",
                        "Compound"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Do you think she is ready?",
                    "description": "The given sentence has a main clause and a subordinate clause. Hence, it is a complex sentence. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple",
                        "Complex",
                        "Compound"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I am anxious to contact him.",
                    "description": "The given sentence has only one finite verb and hence one clause. So it is a simple sentence.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple",
                        "Complex",
                        "Compound"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I noticed that he seemed to be drinking a lot.",
                    "description": "The given sentence has a main clause and a subordinate clause. Hence, it is a complex sentence. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple",
                        "Complex",
                        "Compound"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "He came to Sydney to look for work.",
                    "description": "The given sentence has only one finite verb and hence one clause. So it is a simple sentence.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple",
                        "Complex",
                        "Compound"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "My father was bitten by a dog last week.",
                    "description": "The given sentence has only one finite verb and hence one clause. So it is a simple sentence.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple",
                        "Complex",
                        "Compound"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I don’t know what I should do.",
                    "description": "The given sentence has a main clause and a subordinate clause. Hence, it is a complex sentence. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple",
                        "Complex",
                        "Compound"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I neither smoke nor drink.",
                    "description": "The given sentence has two co-ordinate clauses connected by the correlative conjunction neither/nor. Hence it is a compound sentence.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple",
                        "Complex",
                        "Compound"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I didn’t sing because she was there.",
                    "description": "The given sentence has a main clause and a subordinate clause. Hence, it is a complex sentence. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple",
                        "Complex",
                        "Compound"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "You can stay or quit.",
                    "description": "The given sentence has two coordinate clauses connected by the coordinating conjunction or. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple",
                        "Complex",
                        "Compound"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "If it helps, I will lend you some money.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple",
                        "Complex",
                        "Compound"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I knocked again and again but nobody opened the door.",
                    "description": "The given sentence has two coordinate clauses connected by the coordinating conjunction but. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple",
                        "Complex",
                        "Compound"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}